OLHA CHERKASHYNA

QA ENGINEER (MANUAL)

CONTACTS



+380977382858



oll9a14@gmail.com



Linkedin



Kyiv, Ukraine Ready to work remotely

PORTFOLIO



Link

Working with: User stories in Trello, test cases in Test Rail, issue reporting in Jira, SQL in SQL Fiddle, API in Swagger & Postman, DevTools

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Mantis Bug Tracker TestRail Jira Postman

Analysis of requirements Creation of test documentation Bug reporting

EDUCATION

Specialist

Hotel and tourism management

Interregional Academy of Personnel Management 2005-2011

LANGUAGES

Ukrainian - Native English - B2

Turkish - C1

SUMMARY

Motivated entry-level QA professional with a background in business management and team leadership. I possess foundational QA skills and excel in creating and executing test cases, conducting various types of testing, and efficiently identifying and reporting software defects. Experienced in web and mobile testing, I am adept at utilizing Jira, TestRail, and Postman for project work. Additionally, I have a strong command of testing theory and possess fundamental knowledge in SQL.

COURSES

. «Software Testing Introduction» EPAM

Sep 2023 - Apr 2024

(Software Testing Introduction, Web-services introduction, Introduction to SQL, Cloud, Version control with GIT, Continuous Integration with Jenkins, HTML, CSS, JS Essentials)

• «The Fundamentals of Software Testing» QATestLab Training Center

Mar 2023 - Apr 2023 (Certificate)

(Approaches to the Functional Testing, Software Testing Lifecycle, Test Design, Test

Practice in testing software, games, mobile and PC applications Describing bug reports in the Mantis Bug Tracker system Working with Jira and TestRail

· «The fundamentals of software testing» Prometheus

Feb 2023 - Feb 2023 (Certificate)

(General concepts of testing, Software development and testing process (SDLC), Types of testing, Requirements analysis, Test cases and test design techniques, Defect tracking and management)

EXPERIENCE

· Translator & Site Manager

Jul 2022 - May 2024

Turkish real estate agency

Translating and managing the company's website content

· Private entrepreneur. Owner and manager of a lingerie store

Jun 2010 - Feb 2022

Management of a women's lingerie store. Organizing a business from scratch Management of the procurement process. Accounting

· Translator from/to Turkish

Aug 2009 - Apr 2010

In a construction company, on the construction of the stadium for Euro 2012 Simultaneous interpretation

Written translation of documentation and correspondence